Guide to the Arturo Islas Papers, 1956-1991
Department of Special Collections
Arturo Islas Papers,
1956-1991
Special Collections M0618
Islas, Arturo, 1938-
18.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access unrestricted.
Provenance
Gift of Arturo Islas, 1985, and the Estate of Arturo Islas, 1991 & 1992.
Biographical Note
Arturo Islas was an English professor at Stanford and an author who explored the Chicano experience of living in two cultures in his novels. He was born on May 24, 1938 in El Paso, Texas, and left with a Sloan Scholarship and to study at Stanford University in 1956. He had intended to become a neurosurgeon, but his ambitions in the sciences gave way to his exceptional talents in literature. Referring to this switch, he once said, So it was that the poor Chicano boy came to teach the Anglos their literature. He graduated with a Bachelor of Arts in English, Phi Beta Kappa, in 1960, and entered the Ph. D. program in the autumn. In 1971, upon completion of his dissertation on Jewish-American novelist Hortense Calisher, Arturo Islas became the first Chicano in the United States to earn a doctorate in English.
Arturo Islas stayed at Stanford and distinguished himself as a teacher, winning the Dinkelspiel Award for Outstanding Service to Undergraduate Education in 1976. That same year, he became Stanford's first tenured Chicano faculty member. Both in and outside the classroom, Islas was a major force in nurturing the growing Chicano community. He was an advisor to many Chicano students, taught courses geared toward their needs and interests, and was active in numerous Chicano organizations. Better known for his courses on American literature, he was a popular lecturer and was elected to speak at Senior Class Day four times.
Outside the Stanford comnmunity, Islas won fame for his two novels, The Rain God, which garnered numerous awards, and Migrant Souls, published in 1990. Migrant Souls was the first novel by a Chicano to be published by a New York firm. After his long struggle against the New York firms to have his Chicano voice heard, his reaction was more of outrage than pride at having cracked the system. In the trilogy of books he was writing, he chronicled three generations of a fictitious Mexican-American family not unlike his own, struggling with cultural duality. His lyrical novels were a new and strong voice for the Mexican American experience.
Arturo Islas was working on La Mollie and the King of Tears, the last book of the trilogy, and another novel, tentatively titled American Dreams and Fantasies when he died of AIDS related complications on February 15, 1991.
Scope and Content
The bulk of this collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, teaching and subjects materials Arturo Islas kept on file in his years teaching and writing at Stanford. The collection also includes materials relating Chicano issues, particularly the Chicano community at Stanford University. Unless indicated as outgoing correspondence, the letters in files are incoming.
Access Terms
American literature--Mexican American authors.; Mexican American studies.
Series Description
- SERIES 1: Personal and Biographical Information
  This first series contains biographical notes, his curriculum vitae, and miscellaneous personal items. Also included is health information, particularly about AIDS.
- SERIES 2: Correspondence
  This second series contains mostly incoming, personal correspondence from 1964-1991. The correspondence takes form in letters, cards, and postcards, with some photographs. They are organized by year, with the exception of a few files Islas kept by correspondent. The correspondents consist of friends, family members, colleagues, and students. Some of his personal correspondence may also be found in the people files he kept. There are also a few business letters that Islas had not catalogued in his subject files.
- SERIES 3: Writings by Islas
  This third series contains manuscripts and drafts from Islas's published books, The Rain God - A Desert Tale, Migrant Souls, and two works in progress: La Mollie and the King of Tears, the last of the trilogy, and American Dreams and Fantasies, a separate novel. Also included in the series are poems, book reviews, and miscellaneous writings by Islas, correspondence with his agent, Sandy Dijkstra, his publishers at the Alexandrian Press and William Morrow, readers' responses, and book reviews for his novels.
- SERIES 4: Notebooks and Classwork
  This fourth series contains Islas's notebooks from his years at Stanford as a student. His notebooks and classwork files contain notes, papers, and exams, mostly from English classes, from 1957-1962. This series also contains his Ph. D. dissertation, Hortense Calisher: On Middle Ground.
- SERIES 5: Subject files
  This fifth series contains Islas's subject files. These are grouped as files of literary figures, teaching/class files, business files (speeches, conferences, and business related activities), Stanford-related files (speeches, awards, and committees), files pertaining to the Stanford Chicano community and Chicano issues, and miscellaneous subject files. Islas kept an alphabetical file of literary figures which contain lectures he used in class. His teaching/class files include files of the many classes he taught, with notes and admistrative papers. The Chicano-related files contain papers on classes, activities, and organizations Islas was involved in, news and magazine articles on Chicano issues. Among these, Islas kept thorough files on Richard Rodriguez and Danny Santiago, two controversial Chicano writers.
- SERIES 6: People files
  This sixth series contains Islas's files on colleagues (mostly from Stanford) and other people of interest, friends, graduate and undergraduate students. The graduate student files mostly contain orals notes and letters of recommendation, and the undergraduates, letters of recommendation and related information.
- SERIES 7: Videotapes, Audiotapes, and Journals
  This seventh series contains videotapes and audiotapes of interviews and readings of Islas, and two inspirational journals.
- SERIES 8: Photographs
  This eighth series contains photographs of Islas, friends, etc. and some artwork by friends. The photographs are mostly snapshots, with some professional black and white photos of Islas.
- SERIES 9: Oversize
  This ninth series contains oversize materials from the collection. It consists mostly framed photos, artwork, and awards, and some miscellaneous items.
Container List
- Series 1: Personal and Biographical Information
  - Curriculum vitae (1985, 1990, and undated)and short biography (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brief curriculum vitae (1990)with floppy disk (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford profile: undated profile, letter (1989)from news and publications service, news clipping (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - News clippings (1976-1990) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and memos: notes, horoscope, etc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Insurance/Attorney: information and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ileostomy (1972-1976):medical and insurance bills, letter, checks (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AIDS info: medical information (1985-1990) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AIDS info: Project Inform newsletter (1989-1990) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - More AIDS info and product info (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family correspondence (1964-1976),mostly from parents, photos (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget book, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v. (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Correspondence
  - Personal File: notes, letters, journal entries, xeroxed literature, manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Edward Bergh (1965-1976):photos and letters (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dean S. Flower (1966-1976):correspondence (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eric (1964-1972, 1975-1977):correspondence (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Paul Skenazy (1986):correspondence (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - JMS /correspondence with Jay Spears (1985-1989):sympathy cards and for Jay's death, news clippings for Spears' death, memorial booklet, letters and writings by Islas (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - JMS (1973-1976):correspondence and memos (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Snakeface, Mathilda, and Biscuit (1975-1985):incoming and outgoing correspondence and illustrations (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letters from the desert (1986-1987):incoming and outgoing (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, not dated:incoming (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (1970-1974):incoming (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (1975):incoming (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (1977):incoming (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (1978):incoming (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (1979):incoming (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (1980):incoming (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (1981):incoming (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (1982):incoming (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (1983):incoming (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (1984):incoming (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (1985):incoming (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (1986):incoming (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (1987):incoming and outgoing (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (1988):incoming and outgoing (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (1989):incoming (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (1990):incoming (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (1991):incoming (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - RESPOND! (1986-1990):personal correspondence and reader responses, incoming (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous business correspondence (1985-1987):incoming (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous business correspondence (1988-1991):incoming and outgoing (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1983 - 1984, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Communications received, 1991 Jan. - Feb., Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Writings by Islas
  - Correspondence - Bob Cornfield (1977-1980):incoming and outgoing (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Rain God reviews (1984-1985) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - John Meyer, (1974-1975):incoming and outgoing (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Novel, n.d.,with chapters: I. Felix, II. Compadres Y Compadres, III. Mama Chona (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dia de los Muertos/ Day of the Dead manuscript, an early version 1975(?),with Angel family tree (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dia de los Muertos/ Day of the Dead manuscript (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dia de los Muertos/ Day of the Dead manuscript (1980) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Rain God, xerox typescript (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Rain God (no title page): combination typescript and xerox typescript (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Rain God: 6 Desert Tales - xerox typescript (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Rain God: A Desert Tale: spiral bound typescript (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Zyzzyva (1985-1989):correspondence with Howard Junker, ed., Stanford Daily article - Zyzzyva' s First Year (1986), The Blind, by Islas (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Sequoia, Winter 1985:literary journal (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fifth Biennial Convention of the American Studies Association booklet (1975) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Zyzzyva, ( Spring 1986,Vol. II, No. 1): literary journal (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Rain God: spiral bound text (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Campus Conference for Eminence in Teaching brochure (1979) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miquitzli (Vol. 3, Issue 1, Winter-Spring Quarter 1975) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miquitzli (Vol. 2, Issue 1, winter Quarter 1974) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letters to and from publishers on Dia de los Muertos, personal letters from readers (1975-1985) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Agents, Book Editors, letters from editors (1976-1984) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Responses to The Rain God (1984-1988) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - On The Rain God (1984-1985):letters, news clippings (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Rain God Reviews (1984-1986) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Alexandrian Press - The Rain God Contract (1984-1987):copyright registation, correspondence to and from agent, sales report (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Rain God/ Promotion and Mailing List (1984-1986) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - William Morrow Contract (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - M. Guarnaschelli, editor, William Morrow (1987-1990):incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dijkstra, literary agent (1986-1990):correspondence between agent and publishers, and correspondence to and from Sandy Dijkstra and Islas (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Peregrine Press - Gibbs Smith: incoming and outging correspondence (1986-1988) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Avon Books/ Contract 1990):contract, correspondence (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Book covers for Migrant Souls and The Rain God (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Migrant Souls Reviews (1990) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Alexandrian Press - Reader Responses to The Rain God (1984-1988) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Migrant Souls (1990):letters from friends, colleagues, and strangers (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls, photocopied pages from (1990) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - La Mollie and the King of Tears manuscript with letter from the University of New Mexico Press (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Menfore: manuscripts and notes (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - works in progress: poems (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Isabel, Emma, Anna, & Albertine: poems, notes, memos (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Island Poem: Finnish Archipelago/Island Poem I, revisions, and notes (1985-1987) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Work: untitled, Flight, Orejas de Paplotte, Tia Chucha (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Dead/Miguel Chico: 2 outgoing letters and manuscript (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Flight/ The Dead: manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Flight: revised manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Blind: Jesus Maria/Christmas Eve, Zyzzyva (Vol. II No.1 - Spring 1986),correspondence, manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Works in Progress: notes, incoming letter (1989),manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Poems (1977): Dancing With Ghosts and other poems, outgoing correspondence (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Works In Progreess: Bondage & Discipline (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Is the Devil Gay?- manuscript (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Miquiztli, 1974:Chicano literary journal (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The Meeting of Saint Anthony and Saint Paul (March 1980):correspondence, notes, poems (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Poems and miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Loneliest Man In the World manuscript (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Reviews: S.F. Chronicle ( 1982-previews by Islas for Distant Relations by Carlos Fuentes and Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter by Mario Vargas Llosa (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Paula Fox: A Servant's Tale (Review): book review by Islas (1984) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Joan Jara: An Unfinished Song, book review by Islas (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Danny Santiago: Famous All Over Town, and Richard Romo's East Los Angeles book reviews by Islas (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Migrant Souls (1988-1990) -correspondence between Islas and William Morrow, manuscripts, and notes (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Margaret's copy - Day of the Dead manuscript (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls (September 1988)spiral bound manuscript (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Souls (March 1989)spiral bound manuscript (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Migrant Souls, 1988, 1989 -spiral bound manuscript (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Flight Into Egypt - copy 1, chapter of Migrant Souls (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls manuscript (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bondage and Discipline - poems (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies manuscript (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies manuscript (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies sections I-X manuscript (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies (I) manuscript (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies (II) manuscript (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies (III) manuscript (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies (IV) manuscript (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - American Dreams and Fantasies (V) manuscript (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Day of the Dead (Fall 1975) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Day of the Dead (1980) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls: first pass pages (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Souls: first pass pages (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Migrant Souls: second pass (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Migrant Souls: extra set (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls: author's set (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Souls (Autumn 1988)excerpt (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Middle of Nowhere (May 1989)from Migrant Souls (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - `Chakespeare in the Barrio or The King of Tears: penultimate draft (1987) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - La Mollie and the King of Tears manuscript___ (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - `Saints,' `Artist,' and Vile Politics: an introduction to Chicano fiction and autobiographical narrative: introduction and 3 manuscripts (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - `Saints,' `Artists,' and Vile Politics... manuscript (1975) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - `Saints,' `Artists,' and Vile Politics... manuscript with comments by Tom Moser (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Feliz Navidad manuscript (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Reading mss: "Middle of Nowhere" from Migrant Souls, 1989, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - The Galarza lecture: On the bridge, at the border: migrants and immigrants, 1990 May 18, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Chile / Arturo Islas. -- p. 42 - 48. -- In Nuestro,1984 Sept., Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    Also includes review article re: The Rain God, p. 48
  - The Rain God: book reviews, clippings, & flyers, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - The Rain God: dust jackets, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 56, Folder 1)
- Series 4: Notebooks and Classwork
  - The Work of Hortense Calisher: On Middle Ground (May 1971):Dissertation for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Class notebook (1959-1961):notes from English classes (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Winter 1962notebook: notes from Renaissance Proseminar, Colonial Literature Proseminar, Development of the Short Story (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Spring 1962notebook: notes from The Later Middle Ages, Seminar in the Romance: Hawthorne and Cooper (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Fiction (1957-1959) -notes and essays (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Class notes and papers (1960-1962):notes, essays, exams (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Class notes and papers (1958-1962) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Class notes and papers (1958-1962) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Class notes and papers (1958-1962) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Autumn Quarter 1956 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Fall Quarter 1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Winter Quarter 1957 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Spring Quarter 1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Fall Quarter 1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Winter Quarter 1958 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Spring Quarter 1958 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Winter Quarter 1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Spring Quarter 1959 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Autumn 1960notebook (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Winter 1960notebook (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Spring 1960notebook (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Autumn 1961notebook (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Winter 1961notebook (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - untitled notebook (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Baxter and Aquinas notebook (1962- 1963) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Spring 1961notebook (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Love of Abstraction: A Brief Comparison (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Autumn 1962notebook (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Theology (1959-1960):Islas's papers from theology class (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Qualifying Oral Exams (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Exams Given, Questions: old exams, qualifying exams for Ph.D. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Burciaga, Jose Antonio. Interview with Arturo Islas, 1990, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 13)
- Series 5: Subject Files
  - Adams, Henry: notes and lectures (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Aguilar, Ricardo (1989):correspondence and resume (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Anaya, Rudolfo (1987):incoming letter (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Sherwood: notes (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Arias, Ron: correspondence (1986-1987),news clippings, book review by Islas (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Bacca, Jimmy Santiago: correspondence, resume (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Baldwin, James: notes, news articles (1967-1988) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Burciaga, Jose Antonio (1980-1990):stories, essays, news articles and book reviews by Burciaga, correspondence (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Calisher: biography, correspondence (1968-1974) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Calisher: reviews (1963-1969) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Calisher: notes, drafts, bibliography (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Calisher: uncollected work, lectures, interview (1965-1971) (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Calisher: Mademoiselle (May 1969)magazine with article by Calisher - Reality (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Cather, Willa: notes and lecture (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Colette: lectures, notes, news clippings (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Crane, Stephen: lecture (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Dickinson, Emily: lecture (1977),notes, Dickinson's poems (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Dreiser, Theodore: notes (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Eliot, T. S.: notes and articles (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - The Erotic in Modern Literature (1976-1979):lectures and notes, including lecture to alumni (May 1979)and lecture for Katchedourian's Human Sexuality course (Feb. 1976) (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Faulkner, William: English paper (1961),notes (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Faulkner and Garcia-Marquez: manuscript (author unknown): The Role of Regional History in Faulkner and Garcia-Marquez, xeroxed articles (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Flanner, Janet: lecture and book review (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Fuentes, Carlos: book review and news article by Fuentes, news articles, notes (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott: news clippings, lectures - including Introduction lecture for Hemingway and Fitzgerald class (1980),Alumni lecture (1983),This Side of Paradise, Great Gatsby, Tender is the Night, His Life: Some Stories (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Forster, E.M.: notes, lecture on Maurice (1975) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Galarza, Ernesto: curriculum vitae and notes (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel: notes, lectures, articles (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Great Novels (Summer 1986):notes, news clippings, teaching handouts (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Hawthorne, Nathaniel (1962-):lectures, notes, English paper (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Lillian Helman (1960)lecture (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Hemingway and Fitzgerald: incoming correspondence (1987),news clipping (1980),lectures - Introduction; 1900, Stanford Reunion (1985), F. Scott Fitzgerald: His Life, Some Stories, This Side of Paradise: Autofiction, `May Day:' Almost a Political Mural in Fiction, Hemingway: the Code Hero and Nick Adams, The Nick Adams Stories, The Sun Also Rises: Drunks in Search of a Novel, A Farewell to Arms: A Modern Fariy Tale, The Great Gatsby: A Surrealistic Romance, To Have and Have Not; For Whom the Bell Tolls, and Some Stories, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Macomber, Kilimanjaro, and the Old Man: Three Killers, Old Man and the Sea, Tender is the Night (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Hemingway, E.: correspondence (1985),articles (1987) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Hemingway, Ernest: news clippings and articles (1984-1985),lectures - Macomber, Kilimanjaro, and Old Man..., The Sun Also Rises, A Farewell to Arms, Hemingway and Fitzgerald: the Code Hero and Nick Adams, notes and articles (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Hemingway (1974-1985):poster, poetry and short stories by Hemingway, articles (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Hemingway/Fitzgerald: introduction and concluding lectures (1982-1983),correspondence, news articles, class handouts and notes (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Hemingway and Fitzgerald (1982-85):news clippings, grades, class handouts, notes, class lists (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Assistants, Hemingway and Fitzgerald (1988) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Hong Kingston, Maxine (1980):interview, narrative: Dialogues with Western Women Writers, The Coming Book by MHK (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Hong Kingston, Maxine (1988-1989):news clippings, MHK interview by Islas, rough draft of interview (Box 24, Folder 7)